hey guys let's solve some trigonometric
equation it says sine of X Plus root 3
cosine of x equals zero so first I
copied it down this has a sine X and A
cosine X in it so this can be kind of
tricky to work with let me show you a
trick for this one if you divide
everything by cosine X sine X over
cosine X is equal to tangent X root 3
cosine X over cosine X is equal to just
root 3 and then 0 over cosine X is still
just zero then we can subtract root 3
from both sides and then we have tangent
of x equals negative root 3. so from
here we can use tangent inverse on our
calculator or we could use the unit
circle if we look at a unit circle we
can see these two values right here are
answers so the x equals 2 pi over 3 or 5
pi over 3. and so this is periodic you
can keep going on forever where we keep
adding Pi a better way to express this
would be 2 pi over 3 plus pi times n and
that is the answer to our question and
we can even click show answer and it
gives us the same answer right there if
you guys want to try more of these I
have this page on andymath.com link is
down in the description how exciting